<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sebastin Santy: GSoC Blog [julia]</title>
    <link>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sebastin Santy: GSoC Blog [julia]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 01:18:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Implement CKAN API and change RegBlock structure</title>
      <link>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 01:18:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week4/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
The fourth week has come to an end. This week was smooth considering the previous experiences I had handling the issues.
Work PR #26: Implemented CKAN API setup. CKAN is used by a lot of government data providing agencies like data.gov, data.gov.au. Hence, adding CKAN brings us atleast over 1 million datasets (800,000 from DataOne, 281,000 from Data.Gov, 28,000 from Data.Gov.au). CKAN was the most successful API we integrated till today, as the API structure was uniform across multiple data sources which is a boon as we didn&amp;rsquo;t need a constructor for each and every dataset separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Implement DataOneV2 Abstraction</title>
      <link>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 01:18:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week3/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
The third week has come to an end. It was a roller coaster week with failing tests and attempts to fix them. Anyways, one of the major work in the project, that is integrating DataOneV2 abstraction was completed. This is the summary of what I have done over the previous week:
Work PR #21: Implemented 2 APIs, TERN(Terrestrial Ecosystem Research Network, Australia) (which features TERN()) and KNB(Knowledge Network for Biocomplexity) (which features ArcticDataCenter() and KnowledgeNetworkforBiocomplexity()) as a part of DataOneV2 API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Work on the REST API interface using DataOne</title>
      <link>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 01:18:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week2/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
The second week has come to an end. This is the summary of what I have done over the previous week:
Work PR #18: Provision to add checksum in Register Blocks. Till now checksums didn&amp;rsquo;t have a separate block of space in the Register Block structure. A new function was created to handle the case of checksums along with the tests. Overall, this PR helped me a lot in learning Julia, thanks to the lengthy review it went through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Making DataDepsGenerators.jl ready</title>
      <link>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 03:56:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/week1/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
The first week has come to an end. Including the previous work, this is the summary of what I have done till now:
Work PR #17: Added DataDeps-based Integration tests. These were needed in order to check whether the Register Blocks we are generating using DataDepsGenerators.jl are in the format DataDeps.jl wants it to be. These tests were crucial as it gives a verification that DataDeps.jl is able to understand the generated Register Block output from DataDepsGenerators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted to GSoC 2018</title>
      <link>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/gsoc-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 02:15:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gsoc2018.sebastinsanty.com/posts/gsoc-intro/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I am Sebastin Santy, a third year undergrad at BITS Pilani K.K. Birla Goa Campus. My proposal for GSoC 2018 has been accepted under NumFOCUS [Julia Computing]. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on adding support for more data repositories to DataDepsGenerators.jl. DataDepsGenerators.jl is a support package for DataDeps.jl which helps in creating Register Blocks for DataDeps.jl. A Register Block is a chunk of julia code which describes the data to be downloaded.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>